Guide to the Oscar J. Falnes Papers MC.135
New York University Archives
Oscar J. Falnes Papers
1902-1989
1917-1985
New York University Archives
Falnes, Oscar J. (Oscar Julius), 1898-1989
MC.135
19.5 Linear Feet in 20 boxes
Oscar J. Falnes (1898-1989) was a Minnesota-born professor of history at the Washington Square College campus of New York University from 1927 to 1966. The papers contain Falnes' personal and professional papers including correspondence, teaching materials, drafts, articles and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The University Archives received this collection in 1990. The accession associated with this collection is 90,015.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series with series 3 further arranged into 2 subseries. The contents of each series and subseries are arranged alphabetically with the exception of Series I, which is arranged according to book size. The series are as follows:
Series I: Books
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: NYU
Series IV: Personal
Series V: Professional
Series VI: Subject Files
Series VII: Writings
Series VIII: Films
Biographical Note
Oscar J. Falnes was born on January 24, 1898, in Wood Lake, Minnesota. He received his A.B. from St. Olaf College in 1921, an M.A. from Stanford University in 1922, and a Ph.D from Columbia University in 1933. In 1927 he joined the faculty of the history department of New York University's Washington Square College. His research specialty was the intellectual and cultural history of Scandinavia, with particular emphasis on the movements of Romanticism, Nationalism, and Imperialism.
In 1941 he took a leave of absence from NYU to join the Office of Strategic Services (OSS) as a coordinator of information, later becoming a senior analyst and head of the Scandinavian-Baltic Research Intelligence Unit. In 1943 he was appointed to the Library of Congress as an associate fellow of the Library on contemporary Scandinavia. In 1944 he joined the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), where he eventually headed the fellowship program.
He returned to Washington Square College in 1947 and worked in the history department until his retirement as Professor Emeritus in 1966. During that time, he served on several planning and evaluation committees. From 1957 to 1960 he was the assistant chairman of the history department.
During his academic career, Falnes contributed numerous articles to journals, periodicals, and encyclopedias, including the Dictionary of American History and Grolier's Encyclopedia International. He published two books: National Romanticism in Norway (1935) and Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize (1938). Falnes was an active member of various professional societies, including the American-Scandinavian Foundation, the American Association of University Professors and the American Historical Association, of which he served as the program chairman for the 1957 annual meeting.
Oscar Falnes was an avid traveler, taking his car on cross-country trips, and in the process collecting a large number of postcards from the places he visited. He died October 13, 1989, in New York.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Some audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Many of the notes in the collection are held together by brittle tape and need to be photocopied.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the personal and professional activities of Oscar J. Falnes as a student, professor at NYU, and scholar of Scandinavian history, concentrating on the years 1917 to 1985. Among the records are report cards, yearbooks, and photographs of his friends, family, and travel destinations; lecture materials, exams, and syllabi from his 39-year career as a history professor; notes, drafts, articles, and reports written for publication; and correspondence with editors, students, and professional colleagues.
Clippings (information artifacts); Film materials.; Scandinavia -- History; Correspondence.; Color slides.; New York University; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration; New York University. Department of History; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; American Historical Association
- Series I: Books
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains copies of Falnes' two published books, as well as books from his personal collection, mostly relating to Nordic history.
  - 5 Years: The Occupation of Denmark in Pictures, 1946; Mentze, Ernst (Box 2)
  - Arbeidar Skandinavismen, 1935; Fostervoll, Kaare, 1891-1981 (Box 1)
  - Belt Und Baltisch: Ostseeische Namenstudien, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Bethany Daisy, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Biblen, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Bismarck, Morrow, Ian F. D. (Ian Fitzherbert Despard), 1896-
  - Carl XIV Johan, 1960; Höjer, Torvald Tison (Box 1)
    Separated Materials
    Includes handwritten notes.
  - Dr. Martin Luther Hans Liv og Gjerning, 1883; Disselhoff, Julius (Box 1)
    Includes notes.
  - Flaskerud Family History, 1939; Falnes, Edna Bjonerud (Box 2)
  - Flaskerud Family History Supplement, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Fredsarbeidet: Hjelpebok for Studiecirklar, Losjar og Lag, 1936; Midtbø, Arent, 1893- (Box 1)
  - Giants in the Earth, 1929; Rølvaag, O. E. (Ole Edvart), 1876-1931 (Box 1)
  - Gods of the Ancient Northmen, 1973; Dumézil, Georges, 1898-1986 (Box 1)
  - Gustav Adolf, 1957; Strindberg, August, 1849-1912 (Box 1)
  - He Who Laughs --Lasts!, circa 1941-1946; Olav, Hans; Myklebost, Tor (Box 2)
  - Historiens Studium I Danmark: I Det 19. Aarhundrede, 1943; Jørgensen, Ellen, 1877-1948 (Box 1)
  - Little Norway in Pictures (1 of 2), circa 1941-1945 (Box 2)
  - Little Norway in Pictures (2 of 2), circa 1941-1945 (Box 2)
  - Mellanfolklig Politik, 1924; Lange, Christian L. (Christian Lous), 1869-1938 (Box 1)
    Includes a handwritten note.
  - Modern Norwegian Historiography, 1962; Smith, Leslie Francis, 1901-1999 (Box 1)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize (1 of 3), 1938; Falnes, Oscar J. (Oscar Julius), 1898-1989 (Box 1)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize (2 of 3), 1938; Falnes, Oscar J. (Oscar Julius), 1898-1989 (Box 2)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize (3 of 3), 1938; Falnes, Oscar J. (Oscar Julius), 1898-1989 (Box 2)
  - Norway's Relation to Scandinavian Unionism, 1815-1871, 1935; Jorgenson, Theodore, 1894-1971 (Box 1)
  - Samlede Skrifter Hundredaarsudgave, II, 1914; Moe, Jørgen Engebretsen, 1813-1882 (Box 1)
  - Sigtuna: Sveriges Aldsta Medeltidsstad, 1941; Floderus, Erik (Box 1)
  - Svenska Fredsrorelsens Historia Aren 1883-1903, Sundblad, Carl (Box 1)
  - Tre år i Kongo, 1887; Gleerup, G. Pagels och E.; Moller, Skildringar af P. (Box 1)
    Includes notes and clippings.
  - Ultvalg Av Norsk Litteratur for Gymnasiet: Welhaven, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Utvalg Av Norsk Litteratur: Wergeland, 1916; Wergeland, Henrik Arnold, 1808-1845 (Box 1)
  - Victory Viking, 1919-1921 (Box 2)
  - Viking, 1916-1918 (Box 2)
  - Viking, 1922-1923 (Box 2)
- Series II: Correspondence
  Series II contains mostly miscellaneous correspondence, as well as correspondence between Falnes and various foundations and editors.
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Erik J. Friis), 1951-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation and Review, 1927-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Editor Rejections, 1932-1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Foundation Grants, 1934-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Landmark Preservation, 1964-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous -- A, 1934-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous -- A, 1946-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous -- B (1 of 4), 1933-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous -- B (2 of 4), 1937-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous -- B (3 of 4), 1927-1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous -- B (4 of 4), 1933-1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous -- B, 1949-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous -- C (1 of 2), 1932-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous -- C (2 of 2), 1937-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous -- D, 1938-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous -- E, 1928-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous -- F, 1930-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous -- G, 1931-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous -- H (1 of 2), 1932-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous -- H (2 of 2), 1932-1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous -- I, 1939-1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous -- J, 1926-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous -- K, 1930-1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous -- L (1 of 2), 1924-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous -- L (2 of 2), 1931-1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous -- M, 1933-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous -- N (1 of 2), 1929-1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous -- N (2 of 2), 1930-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous -- O-P, 1928-1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous -- Q-R, 1926-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous -- S (1 of 3), 1916-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous -- S (2 of 3), 1933-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous -- S (3 of 3), 1930-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous -- T-U, 1934-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous -- W (1 of 2), 1927-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous -- W (2 of 2), 1937-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous -- W, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace, 1936-1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize -- AMS Book Printing, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Norway and the Nobel Peace Prize -- Columbia University Press Correspondence, 1937-1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Norway and the Norway Peace Prize -- Sources, Undated, 1923-1934 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Norwegian-American Historical Association (Magnus Bjorndal), 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Professional Invitations and Solicitations, 1939-1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Publisher Fees and Royalties, 1958-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Publishers -- Queries and Orders, 1935-1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Requests for Reprints, 1938-1944 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Society for the Advancement of Scandinavian Studies, 1967-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III: NYU
  Series III contains materials from committees, clubs and other NYU related materials not directly associated with courses taught by Falnes and lecture notes, exam blanks, assignments, seating charts, and other materials related to Falnes' teaching functions.
  - Administrative
    Subseries 1 contains materials from committees, clubs and other NYU related materials not directly associated with courses taught by Falnes.
    - Activism -- Vietnam and Labor Issues, 1967-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Associated Press Clipping, 1936-1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence -- Alexander Baltzly and Dean Joseph Park, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Directing Committee, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Gallatin Division/Program on Coordinated Liberal Studies, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Honorary Historical Society, 1957-1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Religious Course Committee, 1949-1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - University Christian Association, 1956-1966 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Washington Square College Memoranda and Procedures, 1949-1976 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Washington Square College Miscellaneous, 1937-1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Washington Square College -- Personnel and College Miscellaneous, 1932-1966 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Courses
    Subseries 2 contains lecture notes, exam blanks, assignments, seating charts, and other materials related to Falnes' teaching functions.
    - Archaeology, Anthropology and Psychology - Darwin and Early Anthropo-Psychologists (General and Class Notes), undated, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Class Seating Charts, 1932-1960 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - European Migration, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Exams and Assignments, 1919-1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Graduate Theses and Oral Exams, 1948-1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - History 1 -- Exams, 1927-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - History 1 -- Notes, Exams Articles and Other Class Materials, 1959-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - History 1 -- Notes, Exams and Clippings, 1930-1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - History 2 -- Exams, 1928-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - History 2 -- Exams, Lecture Notes, Reading Lists, 1947-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - History 8 -- Exams, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - History 10 -- Lecture Notes, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - History 11 -- Renaissance and Reformation Lecture Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - History 13 -- Lecture Notes (1 of 2), circa 1920s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - History 13 -- Lecture Notes (2 of 2), circa 1920s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - History 13 and 14 -- Clippings and Readings, 1943-1966 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - History 13 and 14 -- Exams and Other Class Material, 1949-1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - History 14 -- Lecture Notes, 1933-1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - History 33 -- Bibliographies, 1950-1967 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - History 261 -- Western and Russian Interests in the Baltic - The Estates on the Rhine, 1929-1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - History 261/262 -- The Great Northern War (Launching), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - History 261/262 -- Notes, Reading Lists, Assignments, 1948-1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - History 261/262 -- Swedish-Polish Instability - Estates vs. The Prince, 1944-1962 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - History 262 -- Livonia, Undated, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - History 269 -- 19th Century Germany Class Notes, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - History 269 -- Articles and Reviews, 1925-1952 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - History 269 -- Class Material, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - History 269 -- Class Notes, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - History 269 -- Europe and Germany (General and Bibliography) 1 of 2, 1951-1966 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - History 269 -- Europe and Germany (General and Bibliography) 2 of 2, 1951-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - History 277 -- Democracy Articulate - Associational Emphasis ("The Causes"), 1950-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - History 277 -- Liberalism, Materialism, Physical Science and Positivism, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - History 277/59 -- The Impact of Darwinism, 1949-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - History 277/278 -- Realism and Naturalism - Religion on the Wane, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - History 278 -- Anthropo-Geography and Early Geopolitics; Shephard Imperialism, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - History 278 -- Classes, Nations, Races - Social Darwinism, undated, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - History 278 -- Doubt and Disillusionment, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - History 278 -- French Novel as an Expression of Conflicting Thought (Traian Stoianovich), 1948 May (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - History 278 -- Imperialism and Geopolitics, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - History 278 -- Leadership and Democracy, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - History 278 -- Nationalism, Racialism and Zionism, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - History 278 -- Newtonism on the Defensive (Science vs. God), 1940-1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - History 278 -- Optimism and Progress - Notes and Clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - History 278 -- Religion Makes a Turn-About, 1947-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - History 278 -- Socialism/Liberalism on the Defensive - Marx, Engels, Fabians, etc., undated, 1950-1964 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - History 278 -- Symbolism and Expressionism, 1959-1968 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - History 278/59 -- Liberalism on the Defensive -- Interventionism-Statism, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - History 278/277, 1950-1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - History 278/277 -- Bohemianism - the Attack on Western Civilization, 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - History 278/277 -- Book Lists, Outlines, Exam Notes, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - History 278/277 -- Class Notes, Book Lists, Exams, 1947-1966 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - History 278/277/59 -- Notes, Outlines, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - History 377 -- Seminar on 19th Century Europe Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - History 377/78, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - History 377/78 -- Class Material and Notes, 1955-1964 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - History 377/78 -- Notes, Book Lists, etc., 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - History 2200 -- Exams, Syllabus and Administrative Material, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - History 2200 -- Class Notes 1 of 2, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - History 2200 -- Class Notes 2 of 2, Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Imperialism Lectures -- Notes, Citations 1 of 2, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Imperialism Lectures -- Notes, Citations 2 of 2, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Lecture Notes -- Crimean War, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Lecture Notes -- Totalitarism, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Lecture Notes -- World War I and the New Balance of Power, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Map Test, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Nietzsche -- General and Class Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Sociology -- General and Class Notes, 1963-1976 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified Class Notes 1 of 2, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Class Notes 2 of 2, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Personal
  Series IV contains material from Falnes' youth in Minnesota, a large assortment of travel postcards, family related correspondence and photographs and a large number of personal diaries.
  - Archival Management Certificate, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Biographic File -- Documents for Emeritus Status, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Biographic File -- Retirement, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Biographic File -- Vita, 1933-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bunad - Doll Cutout, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Vitas and Biographical Sketches for Publication, 1941-1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Columbia University (Dissertation), 1 of 2, 1925-1934 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University (Dissertation), 2 of 2, 1925-1949 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Berg (Estate Matters), 1932-1974 (Box 7, Box 11)
  - Correspondence -- Christmas and Seasons Greeting Cards, 1 of 2, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Christmas and Seasons Greeting Cards, 2 of 2, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence -- Falnes, Augusta (1 of 2), 1938-1947 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Falnes, Augusta (2 of 2), 1947-1958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Falnes, Hans J., 1921-1952 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Falnes, Hans J., 1917-1947 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence -- Family History and Other Miscellaneous (1 of 3), 1928-1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence -- Family History and Other Miscellaneous (2 of 3), 1971-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence -- Family History and Other Miscellaneous (3 of 3), 1936-1988 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence -- Mathieson, Evelyn (1 of 4), 1935-1950 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence -- Mathieson, Evelyn (2 of 4), 1952-1967 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence -- Mathieson, Evelyn (3 of 4), 1968-1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence -- Mathieson, Evelyn (4 of 4), 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, 1943-1952 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Diary 1, 1918 November-1919 August (Box 14)
  - Diary 2, 1919 August-1920 April (Box 14)
  - Diary 3, 1920 April-1921 November (Box 14)
  - Diary 4, 1921 November-1922 November (Box 14)
  - Diary 5, 1922 November-1924 February (Box 14)
  - Diary 6, 1924 February-1926 March (Box 14)
  - Diary 7, 1926 March-1927 July (Box 14)
  - Diary 8, 1927 July-1928 September (Box 14)
  - Diary 9, 1928 September-December
  - Diary 10, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Diary 11, 1932 (Box 14)
  - Diary 12, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Diary 13, 1934 June (Box 14)
  - Diary 14, 1936 (Box 14)
  - Diary 15, 1936 (Box 14)
  - Diary 16, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Diary 17 -- 1937 Motor Trip to Mexico (Box 15)
  - Diary 18, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Diary 19, Circa 1939-1940 (Box 15)
  - Diary 20, Circa 1939-1940 (Box 15)
  - Diary 21, 1941 (Box 15)
  - Diary 22, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Diary 23, 1943 (Box 15)
  - Diary 24, 1944 (Box 15)
  - Diary 25, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Diary 26, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Diary 27, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Diary 28, 1948 (Box 15)
  - Diary -- Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Diary -- Miscellaneous, 1922-1934 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Driver Licences, 1940-1953 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Dyer B. Lake, undated; 1927-1955 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Dyer B. Lake, 1945 February 28 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Anacostia (E. Washington Baptist Church), 1942-1947 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Childhood, School and Other Miscellaneous, 1908-1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Inheritance from Oscar Berg, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- New York School of Interior Decoration Album, undated; 1936-1942 (Box 18)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- New York School of Interior Decoration Home Study Course, 1 of 3, 1931-1936 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- New York School of Interior Decoration Home Study Course, 2 of 3, 1929-1936 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- New York School of Interior Decoration Home Study Course, 3 of 3, 1934-1936 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Notebooks on James and Anna of Denmark, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Sketchbook, undated (Box 18)
  - Falnes, Augusta -- Truman OPA Letter, 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Falnes' Grades, Report Cards and Exams (First Grade to Graduate School), 1902-1940 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Falnes' Reports and Exams as Student (1 of 2), 1920-1926 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Falnes' Reports and Exams as Student (2 of 2), 1920-1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Flaskerud Family Reunion Notices, 1939-1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Graduation and Commencement Invitations (1 of 2), 1915-1926 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Graduation and Commencement Invitations (2 of 2), 1912-1922 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Invitations and Announcements (1 of 2), 1915-1963 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Invitations and Announcements (2 of 2), 1917-1948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Job Queries, 1927-1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Leland Stanford Junior University Diploma of Graduation, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Postcards, Letters, and Invitations (1 of 2), 1938-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Postcards, Letters, and Invitations (2 of 2), 1936-1954 (Box 8, Folder 11)